Live or die on this day.
The Grey is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Joe Carnahan.
Following a grueling five-week shift at an Alaskan oil refinery, workers led by
sharpshooter John Ottway are flying home for a much-needed vacation.
But a brutal storm causes their plane to crash in the frozen
wilderness, and only eight men, including Ottway, survive.
As they trek southward toward civilization and safety, Ottway and his companions must
battle mortal injuries, the icy elements, and a pack of hungry wolves.
John Ottway, played by Liam Neeson.
Jerome Talget, played by Dermot Mulroney.
John Diaz, played by Frank Grillo.
Pete Henrick, played by Dallas Roberts.
Jackson Burke, played by Nonso Anozie.
Luke Lewenden, played by James Badge Dale.
The Grey is a 2011 survival thriller film co-written, produced and directed by Joe Carnahan, and starring Liam
Neeson, Frank Grillo, Dermot Mulroney, Dallas Roberts, Joe Anderson, Nonso Anozie, and James Badge Dale.
It is based on the short story "Ghost Walker" by Ian MacKenzie
Jeffers, who also co-wrote the screenplay with Carnahan.
The story follows a number of oil-men stranded in Alaska after a plane crash who must survive a
pack of Canadian grey wolves, stalking them during the mercilessly cold weather.
Released in the United States on January 27, 2012, the film received positive reviews,
with praise for its philosophical themes, and for Liam Neeson's performance.
It grossed $81 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of wolf, flashback, alaska,
airplane crash, struggle for survival.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.